<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks on Jesse Szwedko</title>
    <link>http://jesseszwedko.com/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Talks on Jesse Szwedko</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jesseszwedko.com/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Go</title>
      <link>http://jesseszwedko.com/talk/go-debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jesseszwedko.com/talk/go-debugging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Talk I gave at the Go Steel Programmers meet-up group in Pittsburgh about
the current state of Go debugging (both traditional debuggers as well as
print/log based debugging).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang ORMs: A survey of the current state of Golang ORMs</title>
      <link>http://jesseszwedko.com/talk/go-orms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jesseszwedko.com/talk/go-orms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Talk I gave at the Go Steel Programmers meet-up group in Pittsburgh about
the current state of Go ORMs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8411754&#34;&gt;Hacker News Discussion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Path to Go 1.1</title>
      <link>http://jesseszwedko.com/talk/path-to_go_1_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jesseszwedko.com/talk/path-to_go_1_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Talk given at the Go Steel Programmers meet-up group in Pittsburgh about
changes in the version 1.1 release of Go with &lt;a href=&#34;https://about.me/sheenathejunglegirl&#34;&gt;Sheena
Smith&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continous Delivery: Reliable software development through automation</title>
      <link>http://jesseszwedko.com/talk/continous-delivery_pitt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jesseszwedko.com/talk/continous-delivery_pitt/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Talk I gave to undergraduate students at the University of Pittsburgh
as part of Computer Science Department&amp;rsquo;s Tech Talk series where industry
members give talks about topics not typically covered in undergraduate computer
science course work. The talk covers the basics of source control, test
automation, and deployment automation using git, Travis CI, and capistrano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract:4237e2cb775c2e768008f7162a3f0cea&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In much of today&amp;rsquo;s technology industry there is a focus on getting ideas from
paper to implementation and in front of users as quickly as possible. This
allows for rapid iteration of the software with real feedback from users to
drive the direction of the project, which features are needed, which can be
improved, and which can be removed. Continuous delivery is a software design
practice that attempts to shorten this cycle time in a way that minimizes risk
through build repeatability, test automation, and deployment automation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I hope to demonstrate the effectiveness of the principles of
continuous delivery by taking us through the evolution of a software design
process using a simple web application to drive the examples. We will start
with a process which uses none of the concepts of continuous delivery and
slowly adds them (using specific tools as examples) so that we can see the
philosophy of each step along the way. Some of the tools that will be discussed
include git, Travis CI, and Capistrano. Attendees will walk away with the tools
and experience necessary to begin implementing the discussed principles in
their own projects at a small scale.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>