<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Jesse Szwedko</title>
    <link>http://jesseszwedko.com/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Jesse Szwedko</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jesseszwedko.com/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the Energy Consumption of Continuous Query Processing with Mobile Clients</title>
      <link>http://jesseszwedko.com/publication/optimizing-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jesseszwedko.com/publication/optimizing-energy/</guid>
      <description>Complex event detection over data streams has become ubiquitous through the widespread use of sensors, wireless connectivity and the wide variety of end-user mobile devices. Typically, such event detection is carried out by a data stream management system executing continuous queries (CQs), registered by the users. In this paper, we consider the situation where the results of the CQs, which are in the form of individual data streams, are disseminated to the users&amp;rsquo; hand-held, battery-operated devices over a shared broadcast medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization of Energy Consumption of Continuous Query Processing with Mobile Clients</title>
      <link>http://jesseszwedko.com/publication/visualizing-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jesseszwedko.com/publication/visualizing-energy/</guid>
      <description>Complex event detection over data streams has become ubiquitous through the widespread use of sensors, wireless connectivity and the wide variety of end-user mobile devices. Typically, event detection is carried out by a central server executing continuous queries. In this demonstration, we focus on the case where users with mobile devices submit continuous queries (for event detection) to a data stream management server which disseminates the results to the users over a shared broadcast medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demonstrating an Evacuation Algorithm with Mobile Devices using an E-Scavenger Hunt Game</title>
      <link>http://jesseszwedko.com/publication/demonstrating-evacuation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jesseszwedko.com/publication/demonstrating-evacuation/</guid>
      <description>Casualties in emergency situations are often caused by panic and in cases where building evacuation is required, they are often caused by a disorganized evacuation. This has motivated us to design a two-layer indoor evacuation system that takes advantage of two technologies all people carry on them, namely, cellular phones with cameras and RFID cards. The proposed system integrates QR-Code and RFID-based positioning with a routing system with mounted terminals and displays for guiding people with RFID tags out of a building.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>